Francisco d'Albertas Gomes de Carvalho

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER

International Institute for Sustainability (IIS). Estrada Dona Castorina, 124 Horto, Rio de Janeiro, Brasil 22460-320

□+55 11 99121 8851 |

francisco.albertas@gmail.com | franciscodalbertas.netlify.app |

franciscodalbertas |

FdAlbertas

About me____

Biologist with a Master and a Ph.D. in Ecology with 10 years' experience working with applied research focusing on understanding how the spatial pattern of human-modified landscapes affects biodiversity, ecosystem services provision and the Climate. Something about policy too.

Skills____

R - MARKDOWN - GIS - DATA ANALYSIS - ECOSYSTEM SERVICE MODELLING - ENVIRONMENTAL RESTORATION - WRITING AND COMMUNICATION - GOOGLE EARTH ENGINE

Languages _____

PORTUGUESE (NATIVE) - ENGLISH (FLUENT) - FRENCH (ADVANCED) - SPANISH (INTERMEDIATE)

Education

Universidade de São Paulo
PHD IN ECOLOGY

Universidade de São Paulo
MASTER IN ECOLOGY

Universidade de São Paulo
Master IN ECOLOGY

Universidade de São Paulo
São Paulo, Brasil
BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES DEGREE

2006-2011

Professional experience ______

Jobs

Laboratorio de Ecologia da Paisagem e Conservação-LEPaC(Departmento de Eco Universidade de São Paulo)	São Paulo, Brasil
RESEARCH TECHNICIAN - SAO PAULO RESEARCH FOUNDATION TRAINING FELLOWSHIP AS PART OF THE BIODIVERSI	TY AND 2015-2017
ECOSYSTEM SERVICE SCENARIOS NETWORK (SCENNET)	2013-2017
Instituto Socioambiental - ISA	São Paulo, Brasil
JUNIOR ENVIRONMENTAL ANALYST (INTERNSHIP) - PROTECTED AREAS MONITORING PROGRAME	2012-2013
Mineral Engenharia e Ambiente	São Paulo, Brasil
JUNIOR ENVIRONMENTAL ANALYST (INTERNSHIP) - OIL AND MINING ENVIRONMENTAL IMPACT EVALUATION	2011-2012

CONSULTANCY

World Wildlife Fund - WWF Brazil	São Paulo, Brasil
CONSULTANCY - MONITORING DEFORESTATION AND FIRE WITHIN AMAZONIA AND CERRADO PROTECTED AREAS	2020-2021
Instituto Socioambiental - ISA	São Paulo, Brasil
CONSULTANCY - MAPPING THREATS TO FEDERAL AND STATE PROTECTED AREAS IN BRAZIL	2017-2018
Klabin s/a Papel e Celulose	Paraná, Brasil
CONSULTANCY - PLANNING ECOLOGICAL CORRIDORS BETWEEN INDIGENOUS LANDS	2016
Bloomberg Philanthropies e Global Road Safety	São Paulo, Brasil

Research experience ____

CONSULTANCY - FLORISTIC INVENTORY OF URBAN AREAS IN SAO PAULO

Publications

- d'Albertas, F., Ruggiero, P., Pinto, L. F. G., Sparovek, G., & Metzger, J. P. (2023). Agricultural certification as a complementary tool for environmental law compliance. *Biological Conservation*, 277, 109847. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biocon.2022.109847
- 2. Pashkevich, M. D., d'Albertas, F., Aryawan, A. A. K., Buchori, D., Caliman, J.-P., Chaves, A. D. G., Hidayat, P., Kreft, H., Naim, M., Razafimahatratra, A., Turner, E. C., Zemp, D. C., & Luke, S. H. (2022). Nine actions to successfully restore tropical agroecosystems. *Trends in Ecology & Evolution*. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tree.2022.07.007
- d'Albertas, F., González-Chaves, A., Borges-Matos, C., Zago de Almeida Paciello, V., Maron, M., & Metzger, J. P. (2021). Private reserves suffer from the same location biases of public protected areas. *Biological Conservation*, 261, 109283. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biocon.2021.109283
- 4. d'Albertas, F., Costa, K., Romitelli, I., Barbosa, J. M., Vieira, S. A., & Metzger, J. P. (2018). Lack of evidence of edge age and additive edge effects on carbon stocks in a tropical forest. *Forest Ecology and Management*, 407, 57–65. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foreco. 2017.09.042
- 5. Acosta, A. L., d'Albertas, F., Leite, M. de S., Saraiva, A. M., & Metzger, J. P. W. (2018). Gaps and limitations in the use of restoration scenarios: A review. *Restoration Ecology*, 26(6), 1108–1119. https://doi.org/10.1111/rec.12882
- 6. Metzger, J. P., Esler, K., Krug, C., Arias, M., Tambosi, L., Crouzeilles, R., Acosta, A. L., Brancalion, P. H., D'Albertas, F., Duarte, G. T., Garcia, L. C., Grytnes, J.-A., Hagen, D., Jardim, A. V. F., Kamiyama, C., Latawiec, A. E., Rodrigues, R. R., Ruggiero, P. G., Sparovek, G., ... Joly, C. (2017). Best practice for the use of scenarios for restoration planning. *Current Opinion in Environmental Sustainability*, 29, 14–25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cosust.2017.10.004